The next true story from the case files of Ed and Lorraine Warren.
The Conjuring 2 is a horror film directed by James Wan.
Lorraine and Ed Warren travel to north London to help a single mother raising
four children alone in a house plagued by malicious spirits.
Lorraine Warren, played by Vera Farmiga.
Ed Warren, played by Patrick Wilson.
Janet Hodgson, played by Madison Wolfe.
Peggy Hodgson, played by Frances O'Connor.
Margaret Hodgson, played by Lauren Esposito.
Billy Hodgson, played by Benjamin Haigh.
The Conjuring 2 (known in the United Kingdom as The Conjuring 2: The Enfield Case)
is a 2016 American supernatural horror film directed by James Wan.
The screenplay is by Chad Hayes, Carey W.
Hayes, Wan, and David Leslie Johnson.
It is the sequel to 2013's The Conjuring, the second installment in The Conjuring
series, and the third installment in The Conjuring Universe franchise.
Patrick Wilson and Vera Farmiga reprise their roles as paranormal
investigators and authors Ed and Lorraine Warren from the first film.
The film follows the Warrens as they travel to England to assist the Hodgson family, who are experiencing poltergeist
activity at their Enfield council house in 1977, which later became referred to as the Enfield poltergeist.
In July 2013, before the release of the first film, it was reported that New Line Cinema was already
developing a sequel with both Farmiga and Wilson signed on to reprise their roles.
By October 2014, it was announced that Wan would return to direct the sequel and
would make his first contribution as a writer in the franchise.
Principal photography began in September 2015 in Los Angeles
and concluded in December 2015 in London.
The Conjuring 2 had its world premiere at TCL Chinese Theatre on June 7, 2016, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 10, 2016, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and New Line Cinema.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed over $320 million worldwide.
A spin-off prequel, The Nun, was released in September 2018, and a sequel, The
Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It, was released in June 2021.
The film explores themes of london, england,
england, 1970s, spirit, single mother.
The tone is dark.